Gvidas Pilelis



Contact

Address:

Klaipėda, Lithuania

Email:

gvidaspilelis@gmail.com

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/gvidaspilelis-04832a16b/

Languages

Lithuanian - Native

English – C2

Russian - B2

Norvegian – B1

Main Projects

https://gvidasgvd.github.io/portfolioPage.github.io/

Hobbies

- Programming
- Reading/Learning
- Traveling
- Investing

Summary

Software Systems Developer specializing in both, front and back end development. Experienced with all stages of the development cycle for the dynamic web projects. Well-versed in numerous programming languages, libraries and frameworks: HTML5, CSS, JS, jQuery, Bootstrap, SQL, T-SQL, C#, PHP, React.js, Node.js.

Employment History

Software Systems Developer at UAB Omega Technology, Klaipėda

Since 05/2020

I am developing software technology and products that help project driven organizations to improve their project execution capabilities through innovative tools and work processes. Working day includes creation of new and development of existing modules, database and applications modeling and of course code debugging.

AML-Compliance Specialist at UAB Western Union Processing Lithuania, Vilnius

December 2015 - June 2019

Conducting research and analysis of complex and critical issues related to patterns and trends in money laundering and other potential risks. Regulatory reporting as mandated by law, policies and procedures of the company. Assisting and reporting the AML compliance team to ensure the company meets compliance requirements.

Client consultant at AB "Swedbank", Kretinga, Vilnius

October 2014 - December 2015

Counseling of private and corporate clients for financial, day-to-day banking, payments, money orders, investments and savings.

Education

Bachelor of Economics, Klaipėda University, Klaipėda

September 2010 – June 2014

Mathematics, English Business Language, Social Communication, Information Technology, Organizational Work and Document Management, Project Valuation, Statistics, Financial Markets, Enterprise Economics, Psychology, Micro-Macroeconomics, International Trade Finance, Economic Policy, Business Law, International Economic Relations.

Certifications

- Exam 480: Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3
- Exam 483: Programming in C#
- Go from zero to hero in Python3 online course
- Baltic Institute of Technology 'Junior Full-Stack developer certificate'